Name of the program: clustering_pattern_recognition_swc.m

Title of manuscript: Spatial pattern recognition of seismic events in South  West Colombia.

Authors: 

Hernán D. Benítez*, Juan F. Flórez*, Diana P. Duque*, Alberto Benavides*, Olga Lucía Baquero**, Jiber Quintero**, Elkin Salcedo** 

*Pontificia Universidad Javeriana, Facultad de ingeniería-Calle 18 No 118-250-Cali, Colombia.

**Universidad del Valle, Observatorio Sismológico y Geofísico del Suroccidente Colombiano, Edificio 331 - oficina 3010.Ciudad Universitaria Meléndez-Cali, Colombia.

Corresponding author: Hernán D. Benítez, hbenitez@javerianacali.edu.co

This toolbox is created to facilitate the analysis of seismic data of Colombia's South West seismic catalog. We implemented this toolbox in Matlab 7.10 and user gets a graphical interface by executing archive clustering_pattern_recognition_swc.m. Examples of use are presented in file user_guide.pdf.